Hello English learners and welcome to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
Hi everyone.
大家好。
My name is Kathryn and today we have another episode of our interview series lessons.
我是Kathryn，今天我们带来另一期面试系列课程。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're taking a look at a very important aspect of an interview.
今天我们来看面试中一个非常重要的方面。
We're talking about salary and money.
我们在谈论薪水和钱。
That's right.
没错。
So this is the end of the interview and we're starting to talk about details of the job.
所以这是面试的尾声，我们开始讨论工作的细节。
Let's check this out.
让我们来看看。
Listen to the dialogue one time and when we come back we'll be talking more about what's
先听一遍对话，等我们回来后会进一步讨论
going on.
其中的内容。
OK.
好的。
Well, I'm sure you have a number of questions to ask me regarding the position.
嗯，我相信您对这个职位肯定有很多问题要问我。
Yes.
是的。
Well, Miss Childs did give me an overview of the position over the phone but there were
嗯，Childs小姐确实在电话里给我介绍了这个职位的概况，但有一些
some details I'd like to clarify.
细节我想澄清一下。
Well, feel free to ask me anything and I'll try to fill in the details.
好的，请随便问，我会尽量补充细节。
Could I first ask about the remuneration package?
我能先问一下薪酬待遇吗？
Yes, of course.
当然可以。
That's quite an important point, isn't it?
这确实是个重要的问题，对吧？
As a junior sub-editor, we offer a starting salary of HK$150,000 per annum.
作为初级副编辑，我们提供的起薪是每年15万港币。
This doesn't include a generous housing allowance also.
这还不包括一笔丰厚的住房补贴。
I understand.
我明白了。
And are there other bonuses included?
还有其他奖金吗？
Well, apart from full health insurance, we do offer a company staff bonus scheme linked
嗯，除了全额健康保险，我们还提供与读者数量挂钩的
to readership numbers.
公司员工奖金计划。
But we could go through all the details of that at a later date.
但我们可以在以后详细讨论这些细节。
Well, Mr. Parsons, I am flexible when it comes to salary.
嗯，Parsons先生，我在薪水方面很灵活。
The opportunity to work in Hong Kong with your company is the most important thing for
能有机会在香港与贵公司合作对我来说
me.
是最重要的。
Excellent.
太好了。
Well, what other questions do you have, Rebecca?
嗯，你还有什么其他问题，Rebecca？
All right, we're back so let's take a look at a couple of words and phrases on Language
好了，我们回来了，现在来看看“语言要点”中的
Takeaway.
一些单词和短语。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
OK.
好的。
So, this first phrase is a set phrase.
所以，第一个短语是一个固定短语。
That means these words often go together.
意思是这些词经常一起出现。
The phrase is remuneration package.
这个短语是“remuneration package”。
That's right.
没错。
A remuneration package.
薪酬待遇。
Rebecca said, could I first ask about the remuneration package?
Rebecca说：“我能先问一下薪酬待遇吗？”
So what's an easier way to say this, Marco?
那么，Marco，有没有更简单的说法？
I guess basically the salary.
我想基本上就是薪水。
That's right.
没错。
But a package means that it's not just money.
但“package”意味着不仅仅是钱。
It's also some of the benefits or the bonuses.
还包括一些福利或奖金。
So this is a way to describe how a person is paid in general.
所以这是描述一个人总体报酬的方式。
That's right.
没错。
So in the remuneration package that Rebecca is being offered, Mr. Parsons said that she
所以在Rebecca获得的薪酬待遇中，Parsons先生说她会
would get a starting salary of $150,000 per annum.
得到每年15万港币的起薪。
OK.
好的。
So this phrase, starting salary, is another fixed phrase.
所以这个短语“starting salary”是另一个固定短语。
We have a lot of these today.
今天我们有很多这样的短语。
That means these two words go together.
意思是这两个词经常一起出现。
Starting salary.
起薪。
So salary is easy.
所以“salary”很容易理解。
It's the amount of money you make either per month or per week or per year.
是你每月、每周或每年赚的钱数。
But what is a starting salary?
但什么是“starting salary”？
How is that different?
有什么区别？
Well, basically that's the money that you would start earning in the company.
嗯，基本上就是你在公司开始工作时赚的钱。
But obviously with time it could change and you can get more money.
但显然随着时间的推移，它会变化，你可以得到更多钱。
So this means that you will start making this much money, but it's possible that in the
所以这意味着你开始时会赚这么多钱，但将来
future you will make more.
可能会赚更多。
This is the starting salary.
这就是起薪。
That's right.
没错。
And well, of course, as we said, it's $150,000, Hong Kong dollars, per annum.
嗯，当然，正如我们所说，是15万港币，每年。
So now we're specifying how often you're getting this money per annum.
所以现在我们明确了多久拿一次这笔钱——每年。
So if it were per month, this might be a lot of money.
如果是每月，那可能是一大笔钱。
That's right.
没错。
But this is how much money she will earn per year, per annum.
但这是她每年赚的钱，每年。
This comes from Latin.
这来自拉丁语。
That's right.
没错。
So per year.
所以就是每年。
So this is the remuneration package she's getting.
这就是她得到的薪酬待遇。
Not only is she getting $150,000 per annum, she's also getting a housing allowance.
她不仅每年得到15万港币，还得到住房补贴。
OK.
好的。
So many of us had allowances when we were children.
我们很多人小时候都有零花钱。
This means the money that your parents gave you each week, $5 or $10.
意思是父母每周给你的钱，5美元或10美元。
Well a housing allowance is a little bit different.
嗯，住房津贴有点不同。
It means the money that your company gives you per month or per year to pay for your
它指的是公司每月或每年给你的钱，用来支付你的
apartment or your house.
公寓或房子。
That's right.
没错。
So obviously the company is saying that, look, we're going to give you a certain amount of
所以显然公司是在说，看，我们会给你一定数量的
money for you to pay for your house.
钱来支付你的房子。
You don't have to really pay for your house.
你实际上不需要自己付房费。
We'll pay for it.
我们会替你付。
So basically it's a benefit.
所以基本上这是一种福利。
It's a part of this remuneration package.
这是薪酬包的一部分。
You get a salary and you get money for your house.
你拿到薪水，还有钱付房子。
It's a pretty nice deal.
这条件挺不错的。
That's right.
没错。
And well also she's getting health insurance and she is also being offered a company staff
而且她还得到了健康保险，公司还提供员工
bonus scheme.
奖金计划。
OK.
好的。
Bonus scheme.
奖金计划。
A bonus is something extra.
奖金是额外的东西。
It's on top of what you normally get.
是在你通常所得之上的。
But a bonus scheme indicates that the bonus changes according to how well you do.
但奖金计划意味着奖金会根据你的表现而变化。
That's right.
没错。
So obviously he's specifying that the bonus scheme is linked to readership numbers.
所以显然他明确说明奖金计划与读者数量挂钩。
So let's say for example Marco sells newspapers.
比如说，Marco卖报纸。
Marco, you sell on a good week a hundred newspapers.
Marco，你一周卖得好能卖一百份报纸。
If you sell a hundred fifty, you get a bonus of ten dollars.
如果你卖了一百五十份，就能得到十美元的奖金。
But if you sell two hundred newspapers, you get a bonus of fifty dollars.
但如果你卖了两百份报纸，就能得到五十美元的奖金。
That's right.
没错。
This is a scheme.
这就是一个计划。
The numbers change.
数字会变化。
Very good.
非常好。
So all of this that we've just talked about, to be clear, is our remuneration package.
所以我们刚才讨论的所有内容，明确来说，就是我们的薪酬包。
We're talking about a salary.
我们在谈论薪水。
We're talking about housing allowance, health insurance and even a bonus scheme.
我们在谈论住房津贴、健康保险，甚至还有奖金计划。
So a package can include these things and much, much more.
所以一个薪酬包可以包括这些，还有更多更多。
CEOs get bigger remuneration packages.
CEO们会得到更大的薪酬包。
They do.
确实如此。
And if you have children, sometimes a part of your package is education costs for your
如果你有孩子，有时薪酬包的一部分会是孩子的
children or a car or computers, things like that.
教育费用，或者车、电脑之类的东西。
That's right.
没错。
So a lot of great stuff there talking about salaries and a little bit of negotiating it.
所以有很多好东西，谈论薪水以及一点谈判技巧。
Why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
我们不如回去，再听一遍对话，一会儿再回来。
OK.
好的。
Well, I'm sure you have a number of questions to ask me regarding the position.
嗯，我相信你有很多关于这个职位的问题要问我。
Yes.
是的。
Well, Miss Childs did give me an overview of the position over the phone, but there
嗯，Childs小姐确实在电话里给我概述了这个职位，但
were some details I'd like to clarify.
有些细节我想澄清一下。
Well, feel free to ask me anything and I'll try to fill in the details.
好的，尽管问任何问题，我会尽量补充细节。
Should I first ask about the remuneration package?
我应该先问薪酬包吗？
Yes, of course.
是的，当然。
That's quite an important point, isn't it?
那是个相当重要的点，不是吗？
As a junior sub editor, we offer a starting salary of one hundred and fifty thousand Hong
作为初级副编辑，我们提供的起薪是每年十五万
Kong dollars per annum.
港元。
This doesn't include a generous housing allowance also.
这还不包括丰厚的住房津贴。
I understand.
我明白了。
And are there other bonuses included?
还有其他奖金包括在内吗？
Well, apart from full health insurance, we do offer a company staff bonus scheme linked
嗯，除了全额健康保险，我们还提供与读者数量挂钩的
to readership numbers.
员工奖金计划。
But we could go through all the details of that at a later date.
但我们可以在以后详细讨论所有细节。
Well, Mr. Parsons, I am flexible when it comes to salary.
嗯，Parsons先生，在薪水方面我很灵活。
The opportunity to work in Hong Kong with your company is the most important thing for
能在香港与贵公司合作对我来说是最重要的
me.
事情。
Excellent.
太好了。
Well, what other questions do you have, Rebecca?
嗯，你还有什么其他问题，Rebecca？
All right.
好的。
So now let's take a look at Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看流利度构建器。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
So at the beginning of the dialogue, Rebecca is talking to Mr. Parsons about the job and
所以在对话开头，Rebecca正在和Parsons先生谈论工作，
she says, you know, I don't really have that many questions, but when I talked to Miss
她说，你知道，我其实没有那么多问题，但当我跟Childs
Childs about the job over the phone, there were some things she wanted to clarify.
小姐在电话里谈工作时，有些事她想澄清。
So how did she talk to her?
那她是怎么跟她谈的？
She talked to her over the phone.
她通过电话跟她谈的。
That's right.
没错。
So this is a really good phrase to specify that you received information or you did business
所以这是一个很好的短语，用来指定你是通过电话接收信息或进行
talking on the phone, not in person.
业务，而不是当面。
OK, so this is a bit strange because we use the preposition over.
好的，这有点奇怪，因为我们用了介词over。
You could also say I'm on the phone.
你也可以说I'm on the phone。
That means I'm talking on the phone.
那意味着我正在打电话。
But over the phone means by phone.
但over the phone意思是通过电话。
That's right.
没错。
Not by mail or email or in person.
不是通过邮件、电子邮件或当面。
But we communicate, we talk over the phone by phone.
但我们沟通，我们通过电话交谈。
So sometimes, for example, people will see a TV commercial with a nice item or device
所以有时候，比如，人们会在电视广告里看到一件好东西或设备，
that they want to buy and they will purchase this object, maybe a DVD player over the phone.
他们想买，就会通过电话购买这个物品，比如一个DVD播放器。
They will call up this number and order it.
他们会拨打这个号码并订购。
Or you can say, you know, I'm really sorry, Marco, but I don't feel comfortable talking
或者你可以说，你知道，马可，真的很抱歉，但我不太放心在电话里
about my banking details over the phone.
谈论我的银行账户信息。
That's right.
没错。
OK, so that means on the phone.
好的，所以那意思就是通过电话。
So then Mr. Parsons said, feel free to ask me anything.
然后帕森斯先生说，请随意问我任何问题。
OK, feel free to ask me anything about the job.
好的，请随意问我任何关于这份工作的问题。
OK, this is a phrase that I use all the time, and I think it's really important when you're
好的，这是我经常用的一句话，我觉得在
in a business context or a work context to say, listen, if you have any questions, feel
商务或工作场合说“听着，如果你有任何问题，请
free to ask.
随意问”非常重要。
It means don't hesitate.
意思是别犹豫。
Don't be nervous.
别紧张。
If you have a question, just ask it.
如果你有问题，就问出来。
That's right.
没错。
So feel free to ask.
所以请随意问。
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
Just ask me.
直接问我。
It's a very good phrase to give someone or to make someone feel more comfortable.
这是一个非常好的短语，用来安慰别人或让人感觉更自在。
Exactly, exactly.
没错，没错。
All right.
好的。
And he said that I'll try to fill in the details.
他说我会尽量补充细节。
OK, so this is an interesting phrase because fill in, you know, on a form, for example,
好的，这是一个有趣的短语，因为“fill in”在表格里，比如，
means put your name in a box or fill in some numbers.
意思是把你的名字填进框里，或者填一些数字。
But here the details, we think maybe maybe I don't know what the details are.
但这里的“细节”，我们觉得可能是我不知道细节是什么。
So to fill them in means to fill in gaps or some blanks.
所以“fill them in”意思是填补空白或空缺。
So like, I don't know all the details.
就像，我不知道所有细节。
Please tell me the information so that I will know them.
请告诉我信息，这样我就知道了。
That's right.
没错。
So what he's basically saying is I know that you have an idea or a general overview of
所以他基本上是在说，我知道你对事情有个大概的了解或总体看法，
how things are.
情况如何。
But if you ask me, I can tell you more specific things that fill in the details.
但如果你问我，我可以告诉你更具体的事情，来补充细节。
Or, for example, we're going to a party on Saturday night, but I don't know where the
或者，比如，我们周六晚上要去参加一个派对，但我还不知道派对在哪里。
party is yet.
派对在哪里。
How about on Friday?
那周五怎么样？
I call you to fill you in on the details.
我给你打电话，告诉你细节。
Very good.
非常好。
OK, so those are the phrases that we've prepared for you today.
好的，这些就是我们今天为你准备的短语。
I think we've taken a look at a lot of great vocab.
我想我们已经看了很多很棒的词汇。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll be back to talk to you a little
我们最后再听一遍对话，然后回来再跟你们聊一
bit more.
会儿。
OK, well I'm sure you have a number of questions to ask me regarding the position.
好的，我相信你肯定有很多关于这个职位的问题要问我。
Yes, well, Miss Charles did give me an overview of the position over the phone.
是的，查尔斯小姐在电话里给我大致介绍过这个职位。
But there were some details I'd like to clarify.
但有些细节我想再确认一下。
Well feel free to ask me anything and I'll try to fill in the details.
尽管问吧，我会尽量补充细节。
Could I first ask about the remuneration package?
我能先问一下薪酬待遇吗？
Yes, of course.
当然可以。
That's quite an important point, isn't it?
这点挺重要的，对吧？
As a junior sub-editor, we offer a starting salary of one hundred and fifty thousand Hong
作为初级副编辑，我们提供的起薪是每年十五万港
Kong dollars per annum.
元。
This doesn't include a generous housing allowance also.
这还不包括一笔丰厚的住房补贴。
I understand.
我明白了。
And are there other bonuses included?
还有其他奖金吗？
Well apart from full health insurance, we do offer a company staff bonus scheme linked
除了全额健康保险，我们还提供与读者数量挂钩的
to readership numbers.
公司员工奖金计划。
But we could go through all the details of that at a later date.
不过这些细节我们可以以后再详细谈。
Well Mr. Parsons, I am flexible when it comes to salary.
帕森斯先生，在薪资方面我很灵活。
The opportunity to work in Hong Kong with your company is the most important thing for
能在香港与贵公司合作是最重要的。
me.
我。
Excellent.
很好。
Well, what other questions do you have, Rebecca?
嗯，你还有什么其他问题，丽贝卡？
Alright so talking about salaries and remuneration packages.
好的，那么我们来谈谈薪水和薪酬待遇。
Now is this a common word to talk about remuneration?
现在，“薪酬”这个词常见吗？
Yes it is.
是的，很常见。
It basically means the way that you are paid for the work that you do.
它基本上指的是你因所做工作而获得的报酬方式。
So remuneration, it sounds like a big long word.
所以“薪酬”听起来是个又长又大的词。
But in America I think we also just talk about salary or compensation.
但在美国，我觉得我们通常也说“工资”或“补偿”。
Compensation packages.
补偿方案。
Ok, so now when we talk about remuneration, we don't necessarily always talk about money
好的，那么当我们谈论薪酬时，不一定总是只指钱，
like in this case, right?
就像这种情况，对吧？
We can receive other benefits.
我们还可以获得其他福利。
That's right.
没错。
And so a lot of times people think of the important parts of remuneration not just to
所以很多时候，人们认为薪酬的重要部分不仅仅是
be the salary but also to be the benefits.
工资，还包括福利。
And so benefits are not the money, they are the other stuff.
而福利不是钱，是其他东西。
They're health care.
比如医疗保险。
We said earlier a housing allowance, even bonuses and things like that or education
我们之前提到过住房补贴，甚至奖金之类的东西，或者
for your children.
子女教育费用。
These are extras and these are a part of the package.
这些是额外福利，而这些是薪酬包的一部分。
Now what would you prefer?
那么你更倾向于哪种？
To have a good remuneration package like these other additional benefits with a low salary
是想要一份像这样包含其他额外福利但薪水较低的优厚薪酬包，
or would you prefer to have a high salary with not many of these benefits?
还是想要一份高薪但福利不多的职位？
Well I think that it's nice to get the benefits and a lower salary because often times at
嗯，我觉得拿福利和较低薪水也不错，因为很多时候在
a company, like a big company, the company can get really good rates on health care.
一家公司，比如大公司，公司能拿到很优惠的医疗保险价格。
So if I have to pay for my health care with my big salary, maybe it will cost me more
所以如果我拿高薪但自己付医疗保险，可能反而花更多
money.
钱。
But if my company pays with the company rate, that means the amount that they pay, then
但如果公司用公司价支付，也就是他们付的那部分，那么
maybe they can help me pay for these things much cheaper.
他们就能帮我以更便宜的价格搞定这些。
And so in the end I make more money.
所以最后我反而能赚更多钱。
Yeah.
是啊。
Actually I've heard some companies that offer great remuneration packages like if you have
实际上我听说过一些公司提供很棒的薪酬包，比如如果你有
children as you said they will pay for their education.
孩子，就像你说的，他们会支付孩子的教育费用。
But many times they would even pay for their child care, like maybe a nanny.
很多时候他们甚至会支付育儿费用，比如请保姆。
Some of them, some of the managers would receive maybe a fuel bonus.
有些经理可能还会拿到燃油补贴。
So they would get, I don't know, $200 extra a month for fuel for their car if they drive
所以他们每个月能多拿，我不知道，200美元用于汽车燃油，如果他们开车
to work.
上班的话。
So I think companies can get a little bit creative and it's not that much that they're
所以我觉得公司可以有点创意，他们实际花的钱并不多，
actually spending but you take it as to being a really good benefit.
但员工却会把这看作很好的福利。
Well that's right and it makes you more I think happy to work for that company because
嗯，没错，而且这也会让你更愿意为那家公司工作，因为
you feel like they're taking care of you.
你觉得他们在照顾你。
Not just they're giving you money, they're actually taking care of you and your family.
不只是给你钱，他们实际上在照顾你和你的家人。
That's right.
没错。
So we're actually a little bit curious to know how remuneration packages work in your
所以我们有点好奇，想知道薪酬包在你们
company or maybe in your country.
公司或者你们国家是怎么运作的。
That's right.
没错。
So please let us know.
所以请告诉我们吧。
You obviously don't have to tell us how much money you earn but if you want to tell us
你显然不必告诉我们你赚多少钱，但如果你想说说
how these things work, where you come from, our website is EnglishPod.com.
这些福利怎么运作，你来自哪里，我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
We'll see you there.
我们那里见。
All right.
好的。
Bye.
再见。
All right so thank you very much.
好的，非常感谢。